<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-06-02T02:24:01-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Russell-Site</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><entry><title type="html">CS4231 Parallel and Distributed Algorithms</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs4231/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CS4231 Parallel and Distributed Algorithms" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs4231</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs4231/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 2</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>This course will examine some fundamental issues in parallel programming and distributed computing, and the relationships between the two. Parallel programming: mutual exclusion, semaphores, consistency, wait-free synchronization. Distributed computing: time, global state, snapshots, message ordering. Relationships: consensus, fault-tolerance, transactions, self-stabilization.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>This is entirely a theory class and it is taught by Prof Yu Haifeng. He has been teaching this class for very long. I feel like this module is just testing your IQ. 40% of the course comes from the midterm and the remaining 60% comes from the final.</p>

<p>The first 3 weeks are just parallel algorithms like Lamport Bakery Algorithm and Peterson’s Mutual Exclusion algoithm, followed by sequential consistency, linearisation, clocks, global snapshots. After midterms, it was all distributed algorithms: Distributed Consensus, Leader Election, Self-Stabilisation.</p>

<p>One thing that is consistently emphasised is how our proofs must be very rigorous. I think if you have done enough math classes, you would know what to expect.</p>

<p>Midterms was ok, but weirdly it consists of alot of questions which just requires you to say Yes or No without further explanation (hence zero working marks). You must be very confident in your intuition. The last question was on something very weird, but it requires us to write Yes (and nothing else has to be done), or No with a proof. Having used up my brain power for the night, I just put yes (and I got it correct). Studying for finals was challenging because there were no answers to past year papers. So, one has to rely on friends to discuss, and if no one knows, then well good luck to you.</p>

<p>I think very random people will get A for this class, because after the finals, no one can be sure if their answer is correct or not. I am not really bothered if I got A or B+. I am just content I learnt alot from this class.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="Comp Sci" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 2" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MA2202 Algebra I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/ma2202/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MA2202 Algebra I" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/ma2202</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/ma2202/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 2</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>This course introduces basic concepts in group theory. Major topics: Modular arithmetics. Binary operations. Groups. Subgroups. Group homomorphisms. Examples of groups Symmetric groups and Cayley’s theorem. Cyclic groups. Cosets and Theorem of Lagrange. Fermat’s Little Theorem and Euler’s phi function. Direct products of groups. Normal subgroups. Quotient groups. Isomorphism Theorems. Group actions. Stabilisers and orbits. Examples and applications. Major topics: Divisibility, congruences. Permutations. Binary operations. Groups. Examples of groups including finite abelian groups from the study of integers and finite non-abelian groups constructed from permutations. Subgroups. Cyclic groups. Cosets. Theorem of Lagrange. Fermat’s Little Theorem and Euler’s Theorem. Direct products of groups. Normal subgroups. Quotient groups. Isomorphism Theorems</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>I took this class because I was unsure if I wanted to go down the Algebra route for my math degree. This class is taught by Prof Chin Chee Whye (CCW) and he is infamous for setting extremely hard papers. I think this iteration was not an exception.</p>

<p>This is essentially an introductory group theory course but I think there was some additions as well. The previous iterations under another Prof did not have group actions but we do under CCW. Essentially if you run out of tools in your basic group theory, you then rely on group actions, cook up some homomorphisms and use certain properties to your advantage to prove something that seem so far fetched.</p>

<p>Homework took up very long for me. That is because I was very disciplined and <strong>REFUSED</strong> to check solutions or find something similar online. Hence, my paper usage for the 5 homeworks (ok 4, the first homework is easy), is ridiculous. Hard work paid off when I scored full marks for all my homework. Its a great sense of ahievement.</p>

<p>One term that keeps getting thrown around was universal property. I can see why it is useful, but I would want to get some examples on how it can be useful. Undergraduate group theory textbooks won’t feature universal property. These pop up usually in books talking about Category Theory. Prof CCW sure loves his “god given homomorphisms”.</p>

<p>For the exams, the midterms was not that hard. First 2 questions were routine, the last 3 is really just examples and techniques. You know, you know. You don’t, then tough luck. I think if group theory ain’t intuitive for you, then the struggle is real. For finals, there were 10 homework-style questions which had to be completed in 2 hours without any cheat sheet. This can be good and bad because it forces people to just internalise everything, but if you are stressed, then your mind can go blank. Personally, I think I did 5 questions properlly. The rest of the other 5 had little to no progress. I think given how much time I spent on the homework, completing the final is very tough. For PYPs, it is very hard to say because they were considerably easier and I could even do all the S-level papers. When I saw the S-level finals (MA2202S , the 5 MC version of Algebra I), I felt that I could do the first 4 questions within 30 minutes. I thus personally think this class under CCW should have been 5MC instead of 4MCs. Again, no expectations. I think I am very fortunate (yes I know, ironic) to have CCW has a prof for MA2202 because I learnt so much cool things the other cohorts missed out on. Though, I question if it was really necessary to put 10 questions into the final. Finishing it was practically impossible for a person who just learnt group theory for the past 3 months.</p>

<p>Here are some quotes of CCW which can be found on other reviews.</p>
<ol>
  <li>“If anyone has been looking at the course schedule page, we are CLEARLY behind. But hey, we shoot the target and wherever it lands, we call it the target, then, we are always on target.”</li>
  <li>“I topped up your midterm marks, like how the government tops up your CPF.”</li>
  <li>“But here we have not yet used the P-ness of the p-group!”</li>
  <li>“If someone puts me on a desert island and puts a gun to my head, this will be the proof i give, not the one in the textbook.”</li>
  <li>To a question on the canvas discussion forum: “That will be 512 boring equations, and no one would bother to read them.”</li>
  <li>“I didn’t come up with this proof, I copied it (just like you guys do).”</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="Maths" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 2" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DTK1234 Design Thinking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/dtk1234/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DTK1234 Design Thinking" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/dtk1234</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/dtk1234/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 2</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>In this course, students use design principles to develop their creative potential and practise design thinking using a people-centered approach to solve problems and create new possibilities. Through practical activities, students will discover tools and mindsets that guide them in navigating ambiguity in a creative process, observing and learning from others in unfamiliar contexts, and generating and experimenting with ideas quickly. While students draw on design thinking as a personal creative skillset, they will also value the impact of design that affords people the opportunity and privilege to shape the world that they, and others, inhabit.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>This is a CHS class I was forced to do in Year 3, since I skipped it in Year 1 and 2. I originally planned for this to be taken in Year 4 but CHS admin says no.</p>

<p>Again, I was surrounded by Year 1s (very young people). However, I tried to make friends with them and give them some actual good advice for university. I also tried to put in effort (so as not to set a bad example unlike my seniors who keep asking me to screw it and SU).</p>

<p>There were the team-based workshops which is basically just tutorials. It was actually great fun which is great to unwind from CP3209 UROP and use your brain in other creative avenues. The pain part is probably the homework submissions. Could be just me, but I think I overkilled with all my reflections with very deep analysis. I basically used Bloom’s Taxonomy learnt from ES2660 and CS2101 (both communication classes from SoC, taken prior). I got an EE for the midterm feedback.</p>

<p>It seems like a high workload class but really, its up to you. I just spent time on it whenever I have that time. For the prototype, I just used some basic items to build my “scented alarm clock that doesn’t ring”, and I think I did ok for the prototype portion.</p>

<p>I think this module is good in a sense it gave me an insight on what designers go through to come up with ideas. Thinking out of the box is very important here. User awareness and systematic creativity is taught. I think if practiced enough, it can become second nature for you. In a sense, I am grateful for this module. I also highly encourage SoC students to take this module, because it has alot of relations to the non-technical aspects of software engineering (which apparently everyone wants to do). I also managed to use the skills I learnt in this class to come up with very novel ideas for my research project which further highlights the transferable skills learnt.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="CHS" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 2" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GEN2002X Total Defence Project Against Threat to Community</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/gen2002x/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GEN2002X Total Defence Project Against Threat to Community" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/gen2002x</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/gen2002x/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 1 -&gt; Semester 2</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>Through the years, the nature of threats has evolved from traditional security, e.g. territorial threats and terrorism, towards hybrid threats, in which state or non-state actors conduct coordinated propaganda, sabotage, pressure, and other overt or covert non-military or military actions to subjugate the target. In this course, students will learn the key concepts of total defence to deal with such threats to a nation’s well-being; identify and articulate a potential hybrid threat to Singapore; and then design, and possibly execute, a community project that could deliver suitable counter-measures that integrate an effective multi-faceted response to the identified threat.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>This module was coordinated by Mr Kenneth Chong. This is a year-long class and it is 4MCs, (2 each semester). I took this module because I find it interesting since I used to work (intern) in defence organisations prior to this.</p>

<p>First semester was just lectures and tutorials + a mini midterm presentation on our proposed solution. Second semester, no lectures or tutorials, just 2 check-ins with Kenneth and our field work. I figured some groups do not really care that much and opted for a pure theoretical paper. My group is very onz (which sometimes tired me out). We interviewed with a NUS Psychology prof and also Dr Lee Cheng from IMH and came up with a solution targetting the mental health state of young Singaporeans which directly impacted the psychological resilience of the country (hence, the threat).</p>

<p>I don’t have much to say except that it drained alot of my energy unnecessarily.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="CHS" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 1" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 2" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 1 -&gt; Semester 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CS3236 Introduction to Information Theory</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs3236/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CS3236 Introduction to Information Theory" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs3236</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs3236/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 2</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>This module introduces the basics of modern information theory. It covers how information can be quantified, and what this quantification tells us about how well we can compress and transmit information without error. It discusses basic error correcting techniques, and information-theoretic cryptography. Topics covered include mathematical techniques, entropy measures, fundamental limits to data compression and noisy-channel coding, examples of error-correcting codes, examples of information theoretic cryptography (commitments, secure computation, key distribution, randomness extraction).</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>This module is taught by Prof Jonathan Scarlett. It consists of a Midterm, a project and then a final.</p>

<p>I think this is a very nice class for those who want to delve into theoretical computer science. Personally, I found that I could solve the questions, but I was unsure why I do certain things. It is simply not intuitive. The content is the same throughout the past iterations, but I find the exams have gotten increasingly harder.</p>

<p>Tutorial questions were quite challenging, but if you have actually practiced, then there should be no issue. There are hints in the tutorial sheet so it might actually help. Personally, I find that I spent a lot of time solving the questions (yes, it is pretty unintuitive for me). I think the hardest tutorials pertain to Mutual Information, and Channel Coding. Channel coding questions mostly tell us to find the capacity of a certain channel and it is the maximum mutual information for some capacity-maximising probability distribution.</p>

<p>Midterms was not so tough, but I realised Prof deducted marks from me for writing useless stuff. When I was doing the questions, sometimes, I scribble random stuff to get ideas and not erase them anyway but well, he does not seem to like it (or even ignore it). I got quite a high mark which he thinks is good, but falls on the median line.</p>

<p>For the project, it was done individually. For the first part, there were not much of an issue as we had to write code to test out the compression for a file compressor and evaluate its compression capability over different types of files. The second part is just writing about some use case of information theory.</p>

<p>For the finals, well, it was considerably tough. I find myself blanking out certain times. Not sure why but I panicked so early in the exam. No calculators were allowed. I did not want to be messy on the paper so I sketched my solutions in the scratch paper and transferred it over. There was not enough time for me to attempt the last question part for 8 marks. I also did not do 7 marks worth as I was unsure what he wanted by proving equivalence of certain theorem. The final was not my best attempt at all. No expectations for this class, though I did learn alot from this class. I gave up caring about grades at that point. I mainly focused on learning and absorbing as much as possible and enjoying information theory (no matter how unintuitive it is to me).</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="Comp Sci" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 2" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CP3209 Undergraduate Research in Computing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cp3209/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CP3209 Undergraduate Research in Computing" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cp3209</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cp3209/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 1 -&gt; Semester 2</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>This year-long course provides an opportunity for students to undertake a substantial research project under the supervision of faculty members of the School of Computing. Through this research collaboration, the student will experience first-hand the challenges and exhilaration of research, discovery and invention.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>This is a year-long research project worth 8MCs (split between 2 semesters). I was under Prof. Trevor Carlson in the Computer Architecture Group. I was more of the theory guy so I do not have any experience or knowledge of computer hardware beyond CS2100 Computer Organisation.</p>

<p>I think Prof Trevor is very nice. He will help you when you ask. I also appreciates that he gives candid feedback on your work and even suggests some ideas on how this can be done. Under him, I learnt alot about hardwares like FPGA. In the research group meetings, alot of PhD students gave presentations on how their work, holiday trips, conference trips etc. Maybe because it is not really my field of study, I was usually quite lost during presentations.</p>

<p>I was also co-supervised by Prof Kuldeep Meel. I think he is a very busy man haha. He sometimes cannot make it for the meetings. He is a big man in the SAT world and now I am learning alot of stuff from the hardware architect expert and also the SAT expert. This research project resulted me in learning so much that no matter how tiring it can be, this is what gave me the motivation to push on despite my already heavy workload.</p>

<p>I think UROP is a good opportunity for people who are’nt sure if they want to do research or just simply want to have a taste in it. Research is for interested people, not necessarily for smart people.</p>

<p>There is a CA presentation at the end of the 1st semester and a Final presentation as well. My main evaluator was Prof Martin Henz.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="Comp Sci" /><category term="Research" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 1" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 2" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 1 -&gt; Semester 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CS3263 Foundations of Artificial Intelligence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs3263/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CS3263 Foundations of Artificial Intelligence" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs3263</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2024/05/cs3263/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 2</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>Artificial intelligence is increasingly integrated in our everyday lives, and becoming a core engine to power social and economic growth. This course covers the core concepts in artificial intelligence that underlie solutions to these challenging, multi-facted problems. Topics covered include knowledge representation and reasoning with uncertainty, preference, and time, constraint satisfaction, games and optimized decisions, human factors, and new advances in integrative AI and responsible AI. The goal of this class is to introduce students to a variety of approaches for solving real-life problems using the tools of AI.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>This class is taught by Prof Leong Tze Yun. I think this is the 3rd iteration of the class. I could be wrong. 30% of the course comes from tutorials, assignments and participation, 20% comes from quizzes, 25% midterm followed by a 25% weightage project.</p>

<p>This module covers more advanced techniques in A.I, like advanced search (online search algorithms, Monte Carlo Tree Search), Constraint Satisfaction Problems, Markov Decision Processes, Bayesian Optimisation, Reinforcement Learning and Generative A.I. I don’t think the content is hard, but executing the algorithms (like Arc-3) can be very tedious.</p>

<p>The tutorials were nothing special. It is just to reinforce your understanding on lecture content, but we have to write out our tutorials answers and submit them. The assignments were not that useful too, because it is just re-implementing lecture algorithms like hill-climbing, monte carlo tree search, etc.</p>

<p>Midterm was considerably manageable, though I panicked (again - you will see this as a very recurring theme for me during exams). When the results were released, I refused to even look at them. But when they were shown on canvas, turns out I did very well.</p>

<p>The main highlight of this class is probably the final project where you have free rein on what you want to do related to A.I. My group and I did a competition entry and used various A.I techniques to solve the problem. We also made our own techniques or additions to the existing algorithm. My group won Best project in the end.</p>

<p>In the end, I guess you could take this module if you are interested in A.I but you might want to take it with friends so that you can learn from one another as some concepts can be quite tough or counter-intuitive.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="Comp Sci" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 2" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MA3238 Stochastic Processes I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/ma3238/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MA3238 Stochastic Processes I" /><published>2023-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/ma3238</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/ma3238/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 1</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>This course introduces the concept of modelling dependence and focuses on discrete-time Markov chains. Topics include discrete-time Markov chains, examples of discrete-time Markov chains, classification of states, irreducibility, periodicity, first passage times, recurrence and transience, convergence theorems and stationary distributions. This course is targeted at students who are interested in Statistics and are able to meet the pre-requisites.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>This class was taught by Prof Wang Wanjie from the Statistics Department. It is a dual-coded class, with ST3236 being the alternative code for Statistics students. Students registered under ST3236 and MA3238 were taught together, took the same exams, and probably graded along the same curve.</p>

<p>This class is honestly not hard for me. I initially had worries how I would cope because I took ST2334 which is not as rigorous as ST2131 (MA2116). So there were concepts like conditional expectation and conditional variance which is unfamiliar with me. My helpsheet included these terms even though it is probably trivial terms for the statistics students or those who took ST2131. Content was easy to follow. Prof said she won’t ask us to prove results, but rather apply and calculate. She also added topics like Monte Carlo Simulation, Poisson Processes and Continuous Time Markov Chains from Stochastic Processes II (MA4251/ST4238) into the class.</p>

<p>Tutorials had to be submitted but I think there is a loophole for doing tutorials. Tutorials were due on Friday 2359 hrs, but the last tutorial was Friday 5pm and by then the solutions were released. I think a lot of students copied the tutorials when it was released after the last tutorial, attended the lecture from 6pm-8pm, then go home, scan and upload the tutorial. I personally don’t do that as it does not help with learning. I always attempt them on the weekend they were uploaded.</p>

<p>Midterms was ok for me. It was not hard but there was 1 question that threw me off. I got slightly above the median and above the mean. The finals was alright for me. I managed to solve everything. At the last minute, I spotted a mistake with my working (a claculation error, how typical), and within the last 30 seconds, I quickly re-did the question and multiplied 2 7x7 matrices in 10 seconds flat and I wrote down the answer just as we were told to stop writing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="Maths" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 1]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MA3236 Non-Linear Programming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/ma3236/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MA3236 Non-Linear Programming" /><published>2023-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/ma3236</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/ma3236/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 1</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>Optimisation principles are of undisputed importance in modern design and system operation. The objective of this course is to present these principles and illustrate how algorithms can be designed from the mathematical theories for solving optimisation problems. Major topics: Fundamentals, unconstrained optimisation: one-dimensional search, Newton-Raphson method, gradient method, constrained optimisation: Lagrangian multipliers method, Karush-Kuhn-Tucker optimality conditions, Lagrangian duality and saddle point optimality conditions, convex programming: Frank-Wolfe method.</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>This course was taught by Dr Lam Xin Yee. MA3236 is a very highly computational class, but it teaches you very nice numerical methods to solve non-linear programs. It has very high relevance to operations research and even supply chain management. There are emphasis on very theoretical concepts such as convexity. The class is split to Unconstrained Optimisation, Constrained Optimisation, numerical methods for solving them.</p>

<p>As far as I recall, the work for this class used up a lot of paper, since the calculations are very tedious. The homeworks take up 12 pages for me and there is very high tendancy for careless mistakes as well. One needs to have a good grasp of minimally multivariable calculus and maybe a bit of analysis (though it is not a requirement. Proofs requiring analysis were ommitted). Overall, I do not think the content is hard.</p>

<p>There is a computer assignment as well, which requires the use of MATLAB. Personally, I have never used MATLAB for coding before. I only used it for Linear Algebra operations (in MA2001). However, it only took me 5 hours to figure out how the file structure and execution sequence of MATLAB and also to complete the homework and writeup. Hence, it was not much of an issue.</p>

<p>I struggled very much for midterms. The midterms were not hard, but perhaps I was very nervous I made a lot of stupid mistakes. I got 29/50 which is like very below the median for the class. I took the midterm 15 minutes earlier than everyone as I had to rush to another venue for another midterm (CS2106). I was so distraught after I got my midterm results that I practiced very hard for finals. I am very glad my hardwork paid off for finals because I got an A for this class when I was expecting a B or a B-. The preparation of finals also took up a lot of paper. Maybe it is worth getting an iPad? I don’t know.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="Maths" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 1]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">HSH1000 The Human Condition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/hsh1000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HSH1000 The Human Condition" /><published>2023-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/hsh1000</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2023/12/hsh1000/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Academic Year 2023 - 2024</em><br />
<em>Semester 1</em></p>

<h1 id="nusmods-description">NUSMods Description</h1>
<blockquote>
  <p>Across intellectual traditions of the world, fundamental concerns relating to the triumphs and problems of social organization and what a worthwhile life is have persisted through the changing circumstances of every historical age. This course introduces you to some of these enduring concerns and gives you the opportunity to engage critically with them through reading and discussing texts and other media. In the process, you develop an appreciation for the complexities of being human as you practice and sharpen useful and transferable critical thinking skills that are useful in a variety of contexts. What is the essence of being human?</p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="review">Review</h1>
<p>The module coordinator was (probably is still) Assoc. Prof Loy Hui Chieh. This is my first philosophy-type module in NUS, and I am taking this to fufill the CHS Humanities Pillar. This module focuses mostly on what does it mean to be human from various different perspectives from different times in history and also different regions of the world.</p>

<p>The most painful part of this module is probably the reading. I just uploaded the pdf of the reading into a text-to-speech software and I just listen to it being read while travelling to and fro school to save time. I think I am glad I took this class because it has helped be form what profs called “Considered Opinions / Thoughts”. There were many new ideas pertaining what does being humans being. <em>The Ones Who Walked Away From Omelas</em> taught me that nobody is right or wrong on whether to adopt utilitarianism, it really depends on what the individuals prioritises as important. <em>Gilgamesh</em> taught me the distinctions that separate humans from the beasts, and that one distinctive difference is that humans are cursed with the knowledge to die, and hence, we should live each day to the fullest. <em>Xun Zi</em> taught me that rituals are what distinguishes humans from other beings. <em>No Exit</em> tells us humans are often imprisoned by the opinions of others, whereas <em>A Number</em> says that each human, whether you are a clone of one another, are still distinct in their own way and personality. Told you this module is enlightening. I think every SoC student should take this class. That is because SoC seemed so liveless and people seemed to be only fixated on \(\) and Leetcode. C’mon, there is more to life than those.</p>

<p>Tutorials were fun, but I feel so old since almost everyone is Year 1 (and some Year 2) and I was a Year 3 in that class. I am mostly very lost (ok, maybe slow) when it comes to thinking about certain responses to the questions. I think maybe my brain is not wired to think as such. Luckily, there was a political science girl in my tutorial group who corrected all my English and gave us very good ideas.</p>

<p>For the project, it was not particularly hard for me, as I already had an idea on what I wanted to present for my exhibition. I was not expecting much from this course because I will probably get wrecked by the cohort (mostly FASS people), so I focused on developing myself in terms of the skills I am expected to learn from the course. Surprisingly, I got an A- for this course, which was surprising given how badly I did for some of the high-weightage quizzes. These quizzes are very abstract and situational which forces us to apply the ideas and concepts (abstract ones) into the respective situations, which obviously makes it 10000x harder. Despite this, effort bears fruit here. I clearly became more human after this module.</p>]]></content><author><name>Tan Kai Min, Russell</name><email>rtkm8168@comp.nus.edu.sg</email><uri>www.russelltankm.com</uri></author><category term="NUS Course Reviews" /><category term="CHS" /><category term="AY23/24 Sem 1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academic Year 2023 - 2024 Semester 1]]></summary></entry></feed>